<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>developer workflow on Dan's Software Engineering Handbook</title><link>http://sehandbook.com/tags/developer-workflow/</link><description>Recent content in developer workflow on Dan's Software Engineering Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 20:39:29 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sehandbook.com/tags/developer-workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Version Control System (VCS)</title><link>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/version-control-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 20:39:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/version-control-system/</guid><description>Development tool. Used to track code changes. Modern and less-modern examples include:
git mercurial subversion</description></item><item><title>Continuous Delivery</title><link>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/continuous-delivery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 08:01:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/continuous-delivery/</guid><description>The essential feature of continuous delivery is that every commit that passes its integration step, automatically gets deployed further to a target environment.
Typically, a target environment is a test or integration environment, before final deployment out to production.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration</title><link>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 08:01:04 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/continuous-integration/</guid><description>A suite of tests run against all commits that are pushed to version control automatically. The primary benefit here is in using tests to catch regressions as early as possible.</description></item><item><title>CI/CD</title><link>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/ci-cd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 07:32:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://sehandbook.com/glossary/ci-cd/</guid><description>A developer workflow whereby code changes go through an automated process after check in.
The first step of the process is integration. Automated tests run, as well as any configured analysis tools.
The second step is delivery. In this case, delivery means automatic deployment of code changes to the next target environment once the integration step completes. Typically, there is more than one target environment, so this process can loop a few times as verification checks happen in each environment.</description></item></channel></rss>